The legend behind the rainbow.
Judy is a drama, history, music film directed by Rupert Goold.
Thirty years after starring in "The Wizard of Oz," beloved actress and singer Judy Garland
arrives in London to perform sold-out shows at the Talk of the Town nightclub.
While there, she reminisces with friends and fans and begins a whirlwind
romance with musician Mickey Deans, her soon-to-be fifth husband.
Judy Garland, played by Renée Zellweger.
Rosalyn Wilder, played by Jessie Buckley.
Mickey Deans, played by Finn Wittrock.
Sid Luft, played by Rufus Sewell.
Bernard Delfont, played by Michael Gambon.
Louis B. Mayer, played by Richard Cordery.
Judy is a 2019 biographical drama film based on the life
of American entertainer Judy Garland.
Directed by Rupert Goold, it’s an adaptation of the Olivier- and Tony-nominated
West End and Broadway play End of the Rainbow by Peter Quilter.
The film stars Renée Zellweger, Jessie Buckley, Finn
Wittrock, Rufus Sewell, and Michael Gambon.
The film follows Garland's career during the last year of her life, when she relocated her stage career to England, coupled with flashbacks of
her childhood, most prominently the shooting of her part as Dorothy Gale in The Wizard of Oz (1939), her most famous film role.
After some initial success in a run of sell-out concerts at the Talk of the Town in London, her efforts
eventually stop making progress and even start to worsen as her health deteriorates.
Judy premiered at the 46th Telluride Film Festival on 30 August 2019, and was released in the
United States on 27 September 2019, and in the United Kingdom on 2 October 2019.
The film received generally positive reviews, with
Zellweger's performance garnering widespread acclaim.
For her portrayal of Garland, Zellweger won the Academy Award for Best Actress, as well as the
Golden Globe Award, SAG Award, BAFTA Award and Critics' Choice Movie Award.
The film explores themes of london, england, drug abuse,
drug addiction, biography, addiction.
The tone is emotional.